UMER NAWAZ

Cell No. +966 598573388

Riyadh - KSA

Email: umer.bahrian@gmail.com

IQAMA: Transferable

Objective:

To obtain a job within my chosen field that will challenge me and allow me to use my education, skills and past experiences in a way that is mutually beneficial to both myself and my employer and allow for future growth and advancement.

Professional Summary:

Organized and capable, has excellent interpersonal skills and the ability to effectively identify screen and recruit viable applicants. Has a Master degree in Human Resources and more than seven years of HR, Recruitment, and Training Experience.

Experience:

Training Officer

Mitsubishi Electric Saudi Ltd

(Elevator & Escalator)

- September, 2017 Present
 - 1. Maintaining training data base (Domestic & Overseas).
 - 2. Coordinating with regions and working on TNA.
 - 3. Coordination with departments to collect the list of nominated employees for particular training.
 - 4. Preparing training materials for training.
 - 5. Maintain filing and record keeping system.
 - 6. Oversee induction training for new employees.
 - 7. Preparing & delivering any course material related to HR and Soft Skills topics.
 - 8. Completing all the required documents for visa processing for overseas training.
 - 9. Preparation of any required reports.
 - 10. Collecting the feedback for domestic and overseas training.

Recruitment Officer

Mitsubishi Electric Saudi Ltd

August, 2015 – August, 2017

(Elevator & Escalator)

- 1. Reviews and Screens employment applications and preparing interview files.
- 2. Coordinate with the department for conducting the interview of shortlisted candidates.
- 3. Issuing E-Wakala & contract for offer accepted candidates.
- 4. Coordinating with the agencies from India, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Philippine to ensure that the visa stamping process.
- 5. Conducting new employee's orientation & Induction upon their joining.
- 6. Updating weekly report for available and hired positions.
- 7. Reviewing and approving job descriptions
- 8. Sourcing internal and external candidates according to relevant job criteria,
- 9. Mining databases, networking, internet recruitment activities, cold calling, media such as LinkedIn and employee referrals.
- 10. Conducting thorough phone-screening of candidates to obtain relevant job related information

- including but not limited to work history, skills, abilities, and education.
- 11. Managing recruitment and visa process activities with oversees recruitment agencies.
- 12. Plan, administrate and execute overseas recruitment trips (Contingency / bulk recruitment) as and when required in different countries i.e. India, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Philippines,
- 13. Follow-up with recruitment agencies for visa stamping & recruitment status of the candidates.
- 14. Acting as key liaison between the Company and overseas Recruitment Agencies on all matters related to overseas recruitment.
- 15. Developing the Talent Pipeline for future openings.

Recruitment Specialist December, 2014 – July, 2015

One Plus One for Recruitment

(Recruitment Agency)

- 1. Interacting with clients for understanding their requirements.
- 2. Sourcing CV's through job portals, internal data base.
- 3. Screening CV's as per the client requirement.
- 4. Conducting Tele-phone interviews of candidates.
- 5. Arranging for personal interviews with the clients.
- 6. Ensure all vacancies are filled with the suitable candidates within the targeted time.
- 7. Job postings, managing job portals, database and advertisement.
- 8. Co-coordinating with the Overseas Agencies to complete documentation for visa process and share the requirements with them in India, Philippines, Pakistan, and Sri Lanka.
- 9. Continuous Follow-up with Agencies to get the desired candidate profiles within given time limit.

Human Resource Officer November, 2011 - April, 2014

Metro Hi-Tech (Pvt.) Ltd Gujarat Pakistan (Motor Bike Manufacturer)

- 1. Overseeing the human resources department staff and handling all issues involving employee complaints or questions that cannot be answered by other staff.
- 2. Conduct employee orientation and facilitate new comers joining formalities.
- 3. Maintain and regularly update master database (personal file, personal database of each employee).
- 4. Maintaining CV data base.
- 5. Coordinating and managing the performance management activities.
- 6. Planning, coordinating & executing recruitment & selection activities / staffing process.
- 7. Prepare & process leave encashment and full & final settlements of exit employees.
- 8. Keep updated on all HR Policies/ Procedures.
- 9. Prepare EOBI contributions statements of regular employees.
- 10. Routine Internal and External correspondence.
- 11. Disseminate necessary information to the employees verbally, or through e-mail.
- 12. Maintaining /Updating Leave Records; Maintain physical leaves application files.
- 13. Conduct first round of telephone interview for the candidates to schedule interviews.
- 14. Prepare and submit all relevant HR letters (appointment, contract/probation end, confirmation, transfer, warning and termination) to employees in consultation with the management.
- 15. Working on claims of Medical Reimbursement (OPD & In-Patient) against the limits provided.
- 16. Issue employment cards to the new hires.

HR Assistant

July 2010 - June 2011

(Federal Government Agency)

- 1. Interact with HR Manager in day-to-day routine work.
- 2. Handle routine email, Fax and Telephone enquiries in courteous and professional manner.
- 3. Establish and maintain computer records, including recruitment, general (sick leave, vacation pay and hourly time records).
- 4. Maintain confidential employee information and records.
- 5. Perform office services such as filing of documents, duplication, stocking of supplies and monitoring of office equipments.
- 6. Scheduling of interviews and ensuring candidates are managed through the process in a timely and professional manner regardless of the outcome of their application.

Qualifications

Academics

MBA (Masters in Business Administration) :2007 – 2010 Bahria University-Islamabad - Pakistan B.Com (Bachelor of Commerce). :2004 – 2007 Punjab University – Lahore - Pakistan

IT Skills

Ms Office

SAP (Front End user – HCM Module)

Personal Details

Father's Name : Haq Nawaz
Nationality : Pakistani
Date of Birth : 07 Nov 1986

Marital Status : Married, Two Child.